YouTube and Euros sport flew me out to
the Paris Olympics and they're
sponsoring the short and I got a chance
to meet some medal winning athletes and
check out their medals the Olympic
medals have a diameter of around 80 mm
and are about 10 mm thick a gold medal
weighs a hefty 550 g but is not made out
of pure gold it's made of silver coated
with six g of gold silver medals are
actually pure silver and bronze are
bronze which is a mixture of copper tin
and zinc embedded in the center of the
medals is an 18 G fragment of rot iron
from the Eiffel Tower on the reverse is
an image of Nike the Greek goddess of
Victory with the Athens Acropolis and
Olympic Stadium behind her as well as
the Eiffel Tower etched in the side it
has the sport and division for which the
medal was presented if the gold medal
were actually pure gold it would weigh a
truly unwieldy 965 G and would cost
$773,000 in Gold alone to produce
considering there's about 1,700 gold
medals to give out over the games it
would cost $123 million just to make the
gold medals